vehix.com 2010-12-31

# Privacy Policy

VEHIX.COM PRIVACY POLICY

Vehix.com (“Vehix,” “we,” or “us”) is committed to protecting your privacy. This Vehix.com privacy policy (the “Privacy Policy”) describes the information that we collect from you through the www.vehix.com website (including co-branded and framed versions of the website and its subsites, the “Website”), the purposes for which we use such information, with whom we may share such information, your choices regarding our use and sharing of such information, and the steps we take to protect your personal information. By accessing the Website, you are consenting to the information collection, use and sharing practices described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Website. Please note that this Privacy Policy only applies to information collected on the Website and does not apply to information which we may collect on other websites owned or operated by Vehix (other than co-branded websites identified as Vehix.com, which are subject to this Privacy Policy), or by means other than on the Website.

**Our collection of information**

_Information collected directly from you_  

You can visit the Website and access the information available on the Website without entering any personal information. However, in order to access certain information, services or features that may be available on the Website, we may require you to provide personal information such as your name, email address, zip code and phone number and other similar information that can be used to identify you (collectively, “Personal Information”). For example, we will collect certain Personal Information from you if you request more information about, or a sales quote for, a vehicle you are interested in. Using the “Sell Your Car” service will also require that you provide Personal Information. In addition, we may collect certain Personal Information if you choose to register for an account on the Website, join our email list, subscribe to our newsletter, participate in special offers, sign up for our chat rooms, message boards or other public venues or send questions or comments to us via email.

We may also collect certain demographic information (such as gender or age) and information about your interests and preferences (“preferences information”). In many cases, such demographic and preferences information is optional. If we ever use any demographic or preferences information combined together with any Personal Information, then such combined information will be treated as Personal Information under this Privacy Policy.

Please note that many of the services you can obtain through the Website are in fact provided by third-party service providers. For example, insurance quotes, auto financing, and credit report services are all provided by other companies not affiliated with Vehix. If you click on a link to obtain one of these services (or other services provided by third parties not expressly mentioned) you will be directed to a co-branded version of their website and the information provided by you to obtain the service will be collected directly by the service provider, 

_not by Vehix_

. Such information will be subject to the collecting website’s privacy policy and practices.

_Information collected automatically_

We may collect information about your visit to the Website, including what pages you view, the number of bytes transferred, the links you click, the materials you access, and other actions taken within the Website.  We may also collect certain standard information that your browser sends to every website you visit, such as your Internet Protocol address, your browser type and capabilities and language, your operating system, the date and time you access the Website, and the website from which you linked to our Website. We do not link this information to your Personal Information. 

**Our use of information**

If you provide us with Personal Information, we may retain and use that information for several purposes, such as information gathering, lead and sales processing, marketing, legal compliance and similar uses.  For example, we may use your Personal Information in order to provide information and services that you request such as vehicle pricing, insurance and financing quotes and information, responding to your questions and sending emails to our email list subscribers. In addition, we may use your Personal Information to ensure compliance with Vehix’s policies and applicable law. In order to offer you a more consistent experience in your interactions with Vehix, information collected via the Website may be combined with information we collect by other means. We may also use your Personal Information to improve the Website, or to make the Website easier to use by eliminating the need for you to repeatedly enter the same information or by customizing the Website to your particular location, preference or interests. If you have chosen to receive communications by email from us but later wish to opt out of receiving such communications from us at any time, simply follow the instructions for doing so included in the emails. We reserve the right to send you certain communications relating to the Website, such as service announcements or similar administrative or transactional messages, without offering you the opportunity to opt-out from receiving them.

**Aggregate information**

From time to time, we may collect and share with others general, non-personal, statistical information about the use of the Website, such as how many visitors visit a specific page on the Website, how long they stay on that page, and which hyperlinks, if any, they “click” on. We collect this information through the use of technologies such as “cookies”, which are discussed in greater detail below, and those described in the “Information collected automatically” section above. We collect this information in order to determine which areas of the Website are most popular and to enhance the Website for visitors. We may also group this information into aggregate visitor data in order to describe the use of the Website to our existing or potential business partners, clients or other third parties, or in response to a government request. However, please be assured that this aggregate data will in no way personally identify you or any other visitors to the Website.

**Our use of cookies; Third party cookies; Web beacons**

Cookies are small files that websites save to your hard disk or to your browser's memory. We may use them to track the number of times you have visited the Website, to track the number of visitors to the Website, to determine and analyze visitor’s use of the Website (including the effectiveness of online advertising), to store information that you provide such as your preferences, and to store technical information useful for your interactions with the Website. We may use session cookies (cookies that are deleted when your browser session ends) and persistent cookies to facilitate your movement around the Website (particularly in connection with information searches) and to store other information useful in administering the session. You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Internet browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser settings to decline cookies or to notify you when a cookie is being placed on your computer.  If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the features of the Website.

Our Website may also contain electronic images known as web beacons - sometimes called single-pixel gifs - that allow us to count the number of users who have visited those pages. We may include web beacons in promotional email messages or newsletters in order to determine whether messages have been opened and acted upon.

We use third-party advertising companies and advertising networks to serve certain ads to you on our behalf when you visit the Website or other websites. These third-party delivered ads appearing on the Website are delivered to you by DoubleClick and 24/7 Real Media.  Please be aware that we may add or subtract from this list of third-party advertising companies in the future, in our sole discretion and without notice to you. Information (not including your name, address email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites, may be used in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. In the course of serving advertisements to this site, our third-party advertiser may place or recognize a unique cookie or web beacon on your browser. For more information about DoubleClick, 24/7 Real Media, cookies, and how to "opt-out", please 

_click here_

.

**Disclosure of your Personal Information**

Except as described below, Personal Information you provide to Vehix through the Website will not be shared outside of Vehix without your permission.  Please note that once we disclose your Personal Information with dealers or sellers (or other third parties that may make their services available through the Website), they will contact you directly to discuss your request. Thereafter, your Personal Information in their possession will be subject to their privacy policies and practices, which may differ from ours. 

_Disclosure regarding service providers._ Vehix contracts with other companies to provide services on our behalf, such as marketing services, hosting websites, sending out information, and analyzing the Website. We provide these companies with only those elements of your Personal Information they need to deliver those services. These companies and their employees are prohibited from using that Personal Information for any other purpose. 

_Disclosure regarding other third parties.  _In some cases, if you have given us permission to share your Personal Information by clicking on the appropriate box or button on the Website, we may make your Personal Information available to our parent or other affiliated companies, or to other third parties (including, but not limited to, our clients) who have products or services that we believe will be of interest to you. For example, if you submit your Personal Information to receive a price quote for a vehicle, we will share your Personal Information with a specific identified dealer or individual seller (if you request a quote for a particular vehicle you found through the Website) or with a number of dealers or sellers (if you submit a general request for quotes). If you later decide that you do not want us to share your Personal Information with these companies please email [deleteinfo@vehix.com](mailto:deleteinfo@vehix.com). 

_Disclosures in connection with acquisitions or divestitures._ Circumstances may arise where for strategic or other business reasons Vehix decides to sell, buy, merge or otherwise reorganize its own or other businesses. Such a transaction may involve the disclosure of personal and other information to prospective or actual purchasers, or receiving it from sellers. It is Vehix's practice to seek appropriate protection for information in these types of transactions. In the event that Vehix or all of its assets are acquired in such a transaction, customer Personal Information would be one of the transferred assets.

_Disclosure for other reasons._ We may disclose Personal Information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with legal requirements or with legal process served on us, to protect and defend our rights or property, or in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of any individual.

Vehix is committed to protecting the security of your Personal Information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your Personal Information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. For example, we store the Personal Information you provide on computer systems with limited access that are located in facilities to which access is limited. We cannot, however, guarantee the security of your Personal Information.

If you register for an account on the Website, you will be asked to choose a password for your account, in which case, your online account information shall be protected by your password. We recommend that you do not disclose your password to any other person. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your password and account, and are fully responsible for all activities that occur under your password or account.

**Choices concerning your Personal Information; Updating Your Information**

If you have registered for an account on the Website, you may view and update and cancel your account information at any time.

There are two ways to cancel your My Vehix account.

1\. To cancel the account yourself, please follow the steps listed below:

  1. Login to your My Vehix account at [https://www.vehix.com/myvehix/Login.aspx](https://www.vehix.com/myvehix/Login.aspx)
  2. At the top of the My Vehix page you will see a link that reads: Edit profile
  3. Click the “Edit profile” link to reveal an “About Me” page. Click the link that reads: Change your email address, password and other site registration options here
  4. On the subsequent page, click the link that is next to the “Membership Status” heading that reads: Cancel your membership
  5. An additional confirmation page will appear. To cancel your membership, click the “Cancel Membership” button. Your My Vehix account will be cancelled

2\. If within thirty (30) days after submitting your Personal Information to us at the Website you would like us to remove such Personal Information from our database please follow the steps listed below:

            1)         Forward the email verification that you received from Vehix upon                                      submission of your Personal Information to deleteinfo@vehix.com. 

            2)         In the subject header type "delete info" and send. 

            3)         Upon receipt of your email request we will delete your personal                                           information within thirty (30) business days.

Please note that after we delete your Personal Information, there may be residual information that remains within one of our databases that may or may not contain such Personal Information, such as information that may be retained in back-up servers or records we may retain for a period of time to comply with legal requirements or with legal process served on us, to protect and defend our rights or property, or in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of any individual. We will not authorize any third party to access or use this residual information for any commercial purpose.]

**Children's information**

The Website is not intended for use by children under 13. Vehix does not knowingly collect Personal Information from anyone under 13 years of age, except for the limited circumstances described below. In the event a child under the age of 13 submits a question to us on the Website and identifies his or her age, we will use commercially reasonable efforts to limit our use of the child’s email address for the sole purpose of responding to the child’s question on a one-time-only basis. However, we will not use the child’s email address to recontact the child and we will delete it from our records once we have responded. If we become aware that we have unknowingly collected Personal Information from a child under the age of 13, we will make commercially reasonable efforts to delete such information from our database.

**Links to other websites**

The Website may contain links to other websites such as Vehix’s affiliates and advertisers. While we try to link only to websites that share our high standards and respect for privacy, we are not responsible for the content, security, or privacy practices employed by other websites.

**Enforcement of this Privacy Policy**

If you have questions regarding this Privacy Policy or our handling of your Personal Information, please 

_[Contact Us](mailto:support@vehix.com)_

.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

Vehix may occasionally update this Privacy Policy. When we do, we will revise the "last updated" date at the top of this Privacy Policy. Vehix will also send an email to all My Vehix members that includes notification of change to the Privacy Policy and a link to the updated Privacy Policy. We encourage you to check this page periodically for any updates. Your continued use of the Website following the posting of updates to this Privacy Policy will mean you accept those updates.
